<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PSICE</title>
    <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PSICE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 13:45:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Pages (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/news/hugo-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 13:45:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/news/hugo-pages/</guid>
      <description>See Part One of the Hugo series
(alternatively, scroll to the bottom of the page and click on the Tagged: hugo link, which will show all the pages tagged hugo).
Sections Each file or directory in /content is section. To customize the content, place a file in /layouts/section. The default for this theme (in the absence of a file in /layouts/section) is to simply make a list of all the pages in a directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMT</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/news/gmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 17:11:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/news/gmt/</guid>
      <description>Added a GMT script for Antarctic mapping 2poles plot along with some notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMT files</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/data/gmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/data/gmt/</guid>
      <description>The outline of the major ice shelves in Antarctica is missing from the GMT datasets. I have included them and made them available in add.tar.gz and greenland.dat.gz.
For example, here is figure showing the Antarctic and Greenland ice sheets (the GMT bash script to generate this figure is 2poles.gmt here.  # ... some set up not shown # draw the world pscoast -R0/360/-90/90 -JG-75/41/4.5i -B45/30 -Dc -A10000 \ -G100/100/100 -X7c -Y10c -K -O &amp;gt;&amp;gt;$out gunzip -c greenland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of our 2017 publications...</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/pubs/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:25:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/pubs/2017/</guid>
      <description>2017 Chai, C., C. Ammon, S. Anandakrishnan, C. Ramirez, and A. Nyblade(2017), Estimating subglacial structure using P-wave receiver functions, Geophysical Journal International, 209 (2), 1064–1079.
Kluskiewicz, D., E. D. Waddington, S. Anandakrishnan, D. E. Voigt, K. Matsuoka, and M. P. McCarthy (2017), Sonic methods for measuring crystal orientation fabric in ice, and results from the west antarctic ice sheet (wais) divide, Journal of Glaciology, 1–15.
Luthra, T., L. E. Peters, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images of Glaciers</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/projects/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 16:07:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/projects/photos/</guid>
      <description>Photo of crack in the Larsen C Ice Shelf (credit: NASA):  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of our 2016 publications...</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/pubs/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:25:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/pubs/2016/</guid>
      <description>2016 Christianson, K., R. W. Jacobel, H. J. Horgan, R. B. Alley, S. Anandakrishnan, D. M. Holland, and K. J. DallaSanta (2016a), Basal conditions at the grounding zone of Whillans Ice Stream, West Antarctica, from ice-penetrating radar, Journal of Geophysical Research: Earth Surface, 121 (11), 1954–1983.
Christianson, K. et al. (2016b), Sensitivity of pine island glacier to observed ocean forcing, Geophysical Research Letters, 43 (20).
Heeszel, D. S., D. A. Wiens, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don Voigt</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/don-voigt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:37:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/don-voigt/</guid>
      <description>Don is a Senior Research Assistant in Geosciences. His background is in Mineralogy with training at Old Dominion University and Penn State. With multiple years in Antarctica and Greenland on more projects than he can remember, Don landed at the WAIS Divide Ice Core Project as Chief Scientist for the 2011&amp;ndash;12 and 2012&amp;ndash;13 field seasons. On the science side, Don studies the c-axis fabric of the ice as part of the study of the physical properties of the WAIS Divide core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maeva Pourpoint</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/maeva-pourpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:35:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/maeva-pourpoint/</guid>
      <description>Maeva is a fourth year PhD student, who comes to us from an engineering background. She is interested in seismic tomography as well as location and source parameterization of seismic events. She is currently working with regional and teleseismic events recorded by the GLISN network to invert for the crustal and upper mantle structure beneath Greenland. Some of the goals of this project are to constrain the source of a high geothermal heat flux observed in northeast Greenland, provide valuable information about the geology within Greenland’s continental margin and obtain relatively accurate velocity and density profiles of Greenland&amp;rsquo;s lithosphere that could be used to invert other dataset such as gravity data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily Schwans</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/emily-schwans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:33:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/emily-schwans/</guid>
      <description>Emily is a second year M.Sc. student with PSICE. She graduated from the Colorado School of Mines with a degree in geophysical engineering, focusing on computational and applied mathematics, geology, and planetary sciences. She is currently part of a collaborative effort to improve both the performance of the Ice Sheet Systems Model (ISSM) as well as projections of Antarctica’s potential contribution to global sea level as a result of external forcing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Pollard</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/david-pollard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:03:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/david-pollard/</guid>
      <description>Dave is interested in numerical modeling of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s climate, including 3-D atmospheric and ocean dynamics, ice sheets and vegetation. He works mostly on paleoclimates, long-term ice sheet variations, and past vegetation-climate feedbacks. He has been at Penn State since 1997, when he moved from the National Center for Atmospheric Research after helping to develop the GENESIS Global Climate Model. Recently he has worked more on ice sheet models, coupling them with global and regional climate models and applying them to Antarctica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Byron Parizek</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/byron-parizek/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:59:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/byron-parizek/</guid>
      <description>Byron is a PSICE alum, an Associate Professor at Penn State DuBois, and is a member of the Department of Geosciences Graduate Faculty. He teaches undergraduate courses in Mathematics, Earth Sciences, and Computer Sciences. His NSF- and NASA-funded projects focus on numerical modeling of ice-sheet dynamics and related Earth-system processes. When not working with students and colleagues, he enjoys quality time with his family, coaching alpine ski racing, playing in the wilds of PA (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brad King</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/brad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:18:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/brad/</guid>
      <description>Brad is the administrative support coordinator for PSICE, specializing in research and budget administration. He has worked in the research administration field since 2010 and earned the title &amp;ldquo;Certified Research Administrator&amp;rdquo; from the Research Administrators Certification Council in 2013. He learned much of what he knows from his retired mentor, Deb Detwiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating To Hugo (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/news/migrating-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 09:43:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/news/migrating-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am moving the PSICE site to a Hugo-based system. Hugo is a so-called &#34;Static Site Generator&#34; in which one writes the content as a text file and Hugo generates the HTML code to put on the server.
Overview of the pages generated by Hugo The theme is stolen from RPAL at Cornell, who have kindly shared their setup. The look is driven by config.toml.
## config.toml title = &amp;quot;PSICE&amp;quot; baseurl = &amp;quot;https://sanandak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Alley</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/richard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 16:12:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/richard/</guid>
      <description>Richard is an Evan Pugh Professor of the Pennsylvania State University, as well as a Professor in the Department of Geosciences. Richard is a glaciologist with training in geology and materials science from Ohio State and Wisconsin. He studies the flow and stability of ice sheets, their climate records, and the way they interact with the landscape. He used to spend a lot of time on ice sheets; now, he cheers for students going to the field and stays home to teach, and communicate with the public and policymakers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sridhar Anandakrishnan</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/sridhar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 16:12:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/people/sridhar/</guid>
      <description>Sridhar is a Professor in the Department of Geosciences and an associate of the Earth and Environmental Sciences Institute (EESI). Sridhar teaches geophysics and glaciology and conducts research in as many cold places as he can convince folks to let him visit. So far he has done most of his fieldwork in West Antarctica and Greenland, with the occasional foray to Norway and Iceland. His interests involve using geophysical tools (seismology, ice penetrating radar, and GPS) to work out how and why glaciers flow in the ways they do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About PSICE</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:25:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/about/</guid>
      <description>Penn State Ice and Climate is an interdisciplinary group of researchers from across the university dedicated to a better understanding of the cryosphere. We are a part of the Earth and Environmental Sciences Institute, with members from the Departments of Geosciences, Electrical Engineering, Meteorology, and others.
Our mission is the educate the next generation of cryosphere scientists and inform the public and other stakeholders on climate issues. Our research mission is to develop the tools and theoretical framework to better project how climate change will affect ice sheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Information</title>
      <link>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sanandak.github.io/lab-site/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact us via email at psice@psu.edu
Here is a photo of the massive crack that eventually led to the formation of the massive iceberg that broke off from the Larsen C Ice Shelf:  Larsen C   credit: NASA
----</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>