<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PSICE</title>
    <link>http://sanandak.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PSICE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:25:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://sanandak.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of our 2017 publications...</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/pubs/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:25:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/pubs/2017/</guid>
      <description>2017 Chai, C., C. Ammon, S. Anandakrishnan, C. Ramirez, and A. Nyblade(2017), Estimating subglacial structure using P-wave receiver functions, Geophysical Journal International, 209 (2), 1064–1079.
Kluskiewicz, D., E. D. Waddington, S. Anandakrishnan, D. E. Voigt, K. Matsuoka, and M. P. McCarthy (2017), Sonic methods for measuring crystal orientation fabric in ice, and results from the west antarctic ice sheet (wais) divide, Journal of Glaciology, 1–15.
Luthra, T., L. E. Peters, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of our 2016 publications...</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/pubs/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:25:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/pubs/2016/</guid>
      <description>2016 Christianson, K., R. W. Jacobel, H. J. Horgan, R. B. Alley, S. Anandakrishnan, D. M. Holland, and K. J. DallaSanta (2016a), Basal conditions at the grounding zone of Whillans Ice Stream, West Antarctica, from ice-penetrating radar, Journal of Geophysical Research: Earth Surface, 121 (11), 1954–1983.
Christianson, K. et al. (2016b), Sensitivity of pine island glacier to observed ocean forcing, Geophysical Research Letters, 43 (20).
Heeszel, D. S., D. A. Wiens, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don Voigt</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/people/don-voigt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:37:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/people/don-voigt/</guid>
      <description>Don is a Senior Research Assistant in Geosciences. His background is in Mineralogy with training at Old Dominion University and Penn State. With multiple years in Antarctica and Greenland on more projects than he can remember, Don landed at the WAIS Divide Ice Core Project as Chief Scientist for the 2011&amp;ndash;12 and 2012&amp;ndash;13 field seasons. On the science side, Don studies the c-axis fabric of the ice as part of the study of the physical properties of the WAIS Divide core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maeva Pourpoint</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/people/maeva-pourpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:35:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/people/maeva-pourpoint/</guid>
      <description>Maeva is a fourth year PhD student, who comes to us from an engineering background. She is interested in seismic tomography as well as location and source parameterization of seismic events. She is currently working with regional and teleseismic events recorded by the GLISN network to invert for the crustal and upper mantle structure beneath Greenland. Some of the goals of this project are to constrain the source of a high geothermal heat flux observed in northeast Greenland, provide valuable information about the geology within Greenland’s continental margin and obtain relatively accurate velocity and density profiles of Greenland&amp;rsquo;s lithosphere that could be used to invert other dataset such as gravity data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily Schwans</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/people/emily-schwans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:33:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/people/emily-schwans/</guid>
      <description>Emily is a second year M.Sc. student with PSICE. She graduated from the Colorado School of Mines with a degree in geophysical engineering, focusing on computational and applied mathematics, geology, and planetary sciences. She is currently part of a collaborative effort to improve both the performance of the Ice Sheet Systems Model (ISSM) as well as projections of Antarctica’s potential contribution to global sea level as a result of external forcing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Pollard</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/people/david-pollard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:03:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/people/david-pollard/</guid>
      <description>Dave is interested in numerical modeling of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s climate, including 3-D atmospheric and ocean dynamics, ice sheets and vegetation. He works mostly on paleoclimates, long-term ice sheet variations, and past vegetation-climate feedbacks. He has been at Penn State since 1997, when he moved from the National Center for Atmospheric Research after helping to develop the GENESIS Global Climate Model. Recently he has worked more on ice sheet models, coupling them with global and regional climate models and applying them to Antarctica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Byron Parizek</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/people/byron-parizek/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:59:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/people/byron-parizek/</guid>
      <description>Byron is a PSICE alum, an Associate Professor at Penn State DuBois, and is a member of the Department of Geosciences Graduate Faculty. He teaches undergraduate courses in Mathematics, Earth Sciences, and Computer Sciences. His NSF- and NASA-funded projects focus on numerical modeling of ice-sheet dynamics and related Earth-system processes. When not working with students and colleagues, he enjoys quality time with his family, coaching alpine ski racing, playing in the wilds of PA (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brad King</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/people/brad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:18:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/people/brad/</guid>
      <description>Brad is the administrative support coordinator for PSICE, specializing in research and budget administration. He has worked in the research administration field since 2010 and earned the title &amp;ldquo;Certified Research Administrator&amp;rdquo; from the Research Administrators Certification Council in 2013. He learned much of what he knows from his retired mentor, Deb Detwiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating To Hugo</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/news/migrating-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 09:43:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/news/migrating-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am moving the PSICE site to a Hugo-based system. Hugo is a so-called &#34;Static Site Generator&#34; in which one writes the content as a text file and Hugo generates the HTML code to put on the server. A reference to another page on the website is thus: Sridhar Anandakrishnan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Navigation</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/projects/social_nav/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 20:09:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/projects/social_nav/</guid>
      <description>Despite the great progress in the field of robotic navigation over the past few decades, navigating a human environment remains a hard task for a robot, due to the lack of formal rules guiding traffic, the lack of explicit communication among agents and the unpredictability of human behavior. Existing approaches often result in robot motion that is hard to read, which causes unpredictable human reactions to which the robot in turn reacts to, contributing to an oscillatory joint behavior that hinders humans’ paths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Situated Gesture and Speech</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/data/gestures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 20:09:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/data/gestures/</guid>
      <description>As a part of our work on unfamiliar gesture recognition, we encountered a need for a large, high-quality dataset of situated gesture and speech &amp;mdash; gestures and speech used at the same time by the same person to describe the same things. Such a dataset is central to our approach to zero-shot learning for gesture understanding (Thomason and Knepper, 2016). As we were unable to find a large dataset of this type, we collected this dataset during 2016 and 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfamiliar Gestures</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/projects/gestures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 20:09:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/projects/gestures/</guid>
      <description>Human communication is highly multimodal, including speech, gesture, gaze, facial expressions, and body language. Robots serving as human teammates must act on such multimodal communicative inputs from humans, even when the message may not be clear from any single modality. In this paper, we explore a method for achieving increased understanding of complex, situated communications by leveraging coordinated natural language, gesture, and context.
Our work departs from the traditional model of gesture recognition in that the set of gestures it can recognize is not limited to the gestural lexicon used for its training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Airship</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/projects/blimp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 20:09:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/projects/blimp/</guid>
      <description>Primary objectives are to (1) build a control system that enables persistent autonomy. (2) Develop a power system that is capable of operating the blimp and processing hardware using attached solar panels. (3) Develop computer vision algorithms to support research efforts, scientific observations of natural phenomena, and path planning activity. A sensor package will be designed with collaborators at the International Livestock Research Institute in Kenya for prediction of drought. Other future applications include surveillance of remote territory and disaster monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Alley</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/people/richard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 16:12:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/people/richard/</guid>
      <description>Richard is an Evan Pugh Professor of the Pennsylvania State University, as well as a Professor in the Department of Geosciences. Richard is a glaciologist with training in geology and materials science from Ohio State and Wisconsin. He studies the flow and stability of ice sheets, their climate records, and the way they interact with the landscape. He used to spend a lot of time on ice sheets; now, he cheers for students going to the field and stays home to teach, and communicate with the public and policymakers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sridhar Anandakrishnan</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/people/sridhar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 16:12:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/people/sridhar/</guid>
      <description>Sridhar is a Professor in the Department of Geosciences and an associate of the Earth and Environmental Sciences Institute (EESI). Sridhar teaches geophysics and glaciology and conducts research in as many cold places as he can convince folks to let him visit. So far he has done most of his fieldwork in West Antarctica and Greenland, with the occasional foray to Norway and Iceland. His interests involve using geophysical tools (seismology, ice penetrating radar, and GPS) to work out how and why glaciers flow in the ways they do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:25:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Penn State Ice and Climate is an interdisciplinary group of researchers from across the university dedicated to a better understanding of the cryosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Information</title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:25:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact us via email at psice@{our university}.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://sanandak.github.io/projects/blimp/splash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://sanandak.github.io/projects/blimp/splash/</guid>
      <description>Who We Are: We are a project team working to build an autonomous blimp capable of long-term independent flight. Our team is primarily student run under the advisement of Professor Ross Knepper. The team is organized into 3 primary sub-teams: hardware, simulation, and software. Areas of interest are high-level motion planning, circuit design, sensor fusion, dynamics modeling, power system design, and computer vision.
What We’re Looking For: At this time we’re looking for students of all levels with interest and experience in any of the following areas:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>