<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Staff on Foundations of Robotics</title>
    <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Staff on Foundations of Robotics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 17:01:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ross</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 17:01:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/ross/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ross A. Knepper is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Computer
Science at Cornell University. His research focuses on the theory,
algorithms, and mechanisms of automated assembly. Previously, Ross was a
Research Scientist in the Distributed Robotics Lab at MIT. Ross received
his M.S and Ph.D. degrees in Robotics from Carnegie Mellon University in
2007 and 2011. Before his graduate education, Ross worked in industry at
Compaq, where he designed high-performance algorithms for scalable
multiprocessor systems; and also in commercialization at the National
Robotics Engineering Center, where he adapted robotics technologies for
customers in government and industry. Ross has served as a volunteer for
Interpretation at Death Valley National Park, California.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>christoforos</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/christoforos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 17:01:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/christoforos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chris received his Diploma degree (equivalent to MSc) in Mechanical Engineering
 from the National Technical University of Athens, Greece in 2013. He is
 currently pursuing a PhD in Mechanical engineering, working on the development
 of motion planning algorithms for seamless navigation of pedestrian
 environments. In the past he has done research on robotic grasping and robotic
 hand design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wil</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/wil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 16:29:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/wil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wil is a second-year CS PhD student at Cornell. He received his Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s
Degree in Computer Science and Mathematics from UVa in 2015. His primary
research interests are in human-robot interaction, multi-agent planning, and
programming languages. He is currently working on a project to perform situated
language understanding, incorporating context from gesture, memory, and other
sources to disambiguate commands from a human.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zhengqi</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/zhengqi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 17:02:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/teaching/foundations/staff/zhengqi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zhengqi is a first-year CS PhD student at Cornell. He received his Bachelor Degree in Computer
Engineering at University of Minnesota in 2016. He is interested in robotics and computer vision.
More specifically, mobile robot navigation, SLAM, sensor fusion and 3D computer vision. In the past
he worked with Google Project Tango on a project of real-time indoor navigation system and a project
of robot vision for precision agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>