<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Cornell RPAL</title>
    <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Cornell RPAL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 17:25:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D. Student Wil Thomason Receives NSF GRFP and NDSEG Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/thomason_grfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 17:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/thomason_grfp/</guid>
      <description>Second-year Ph.D. student Wil Thomason was awarded a four-year fellowship through the National Defense Science and Engineering Graduate Fellowship. He also received a three-year fellowship through the National Science Foundation&amp;rsquo;s Graduate Research Fellowship Program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Nominated for Best Paper Award at HRI 2017</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017_nominated_best_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 17:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017_nominated_best_paper/</guid>
      <description>The paper &amp;ldquo;Implicit Communication in a Joint Action&amp;rdquo;, by Ross Knepper, Christoforos Mavrogiannis, Julia Proft, and Claire Liang, has been nominated for a Best Paper Award at HRI 2017.
For more on the paper, please see the announcement of its acceptance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Accepted to HRI 2017</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 23:47:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017/</guid>
      <description>The paper &amp;ldquo;Implicit Communication in a Joint Action&amp;rdquo;, by Ross Knepper, Christoforos Mavrogiannis, Julia Proft, and Claire Liang, has been accepted to HRI 2017.
From the paper:
 Actions performed in the context of a joint activity comprise two aspects: functional and communicative. The functional component achieves the goal of the action, whereas its communicative component, when present, expresses some information to the actor’s partners in the joint activity. The interpretation of such communication requires leveraging information that is public to all participants, known as common ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Presented at WAFR 2016</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/wafr2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 23:47:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/wafr2016/</guid>
      <description>The paper &amp;ldquo;Decentralized Multi-Agent Navigation Planning with Braids&amp;rdquo;, by Christoforos Mavrogiannis and Ross Knepper, was presented at WAFR 2016.
From the paper:
 We present a novel planning framework for navigation in dynamic, multi-agent environments with no explicit communication among agents, such as pedestrian scenes. Inspired by the collaborative nature of human navigation, our approach treats the problem as a coordination game, in which players coordinate to avoid each other as they move towards their destinations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>