<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Cornell RPAL</title>
    <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Cornell RPAL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 17:25:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Nominated for Best Paper Award at HRI 2017</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017_nominated_best_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 17:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017_nominated_best_paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paper &amp;ldquo;Implicit Communication in a Joint Action&amp;rdquo;, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/ross/&#34;&gt;Ross Knepper&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/chris/&#34;&gt;Christoforos Mavrogiannis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/julia/&#34;&gt;Julia Proft&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/claire/&#34;&gt;Claire Liang&lt;/a&gt;, has been nominated for a &lt;strong&gt;Best Paper Award&lt;/strong&gt; at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://humanrobotinteraction.org/2017/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HRI 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the paper, please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017/&#34;&gt;the announcement of its acceptance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Accepted to HRI 2017</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 23:47:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/hri2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paper &amp;ldquo;Implicit Communication in a Joint Action&amp;rdquo;, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/ross/&#34;&gt;Ross Knepper&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/chris/&#34;&gt;Christoforos Mavrogiannis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/julia/&#34;&gt;Julia Proft&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/claire/&#34;&gt;Claire Liang&lt;/a&gt;, has been accepted to &lt;a href=&#34;http://humanrobotinteraction.org/2017/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HRI
2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the paper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actions performed in the context of a joint activity comprise two aspects: functional and
communicative. The functional component achieves the goal of the action, whereas its
communicative component, when present, expresses some information to the actor’s partners in the
joint activity. The interpretation of such communication requires leveraging information that is
public to all participants, known as common ground. Much of human communication is performed
through this implicit mechanism, and humans cannot help but infer some meaning — whether or not
it was intended by the actor — from most actions. Robots must be cognizant of how their actions
will be interpreted in context. We present a framework for robots to utilize this communicative
channel on top of normal functional actions to work more effectively with human partners. We
consider the role of the actor and the observer, both individually and jointly, in implicit
communication, as well as the effects of timing. We also show how the framework maps onto
various modes of action, including natural language and motion. We consider these modes of
action in various human-robot interaction domains, including social navigation and collaborative
assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Presented at WAFR 2016</title>
      <link>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/wafr2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 23:47:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/news/wafr2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paper &lt;a href=&#34;http://wafr.org/papers/WAFR_2016_paper_117.pdf&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Decentralized Multi-Agent Navigation Planning with
Braids&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/chris/&#34;&gt;Christoforos Mavrogiannis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpal.cs.cornell.edu/people/ross/&#34;&gt;Ross Knepper&lt;/a&gt;, was presented at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wafr.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WAFR
2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the paper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present a novel planning framework for navigation in dynamic,
multi-agent environments with no explicit communication among agents, such as
pedestrian scenes. Inspired by the collaborative nature of human navigation, our
approach treats the problem as a coordination game, in which players coordinate
to avoid each other as they move towards their destinations. We explicitly encode
the concept of coordination into the agents’ decision making process through a
novel inference mechanism about future joint strategies of avoidance. We represent
joint strategies as equivalence classes of topological trajectory patterns using
the formalism of braids. This topological representation naturally generalizes to
any number of agents and provides the advantage of adaptability to different environments,
in contrast to the majority of existing approaches. At every round,
the agents simultaneously decide on their next action that contributes collision-free
progress towards their destination but also towards a global joint strategy
that appears to be in compliance with all agents’ preferences, as inferred from
their past behaviors. This policy leads to a smooth and rapid uncertainty decrease
regarding the emerging joint strategy that is promising for real world scenarios.
Simulation results highlight the importance of reasoning about joint strategies
and demonstrate the efficacy of our approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>